dealer.com 2019-12-25

# Dealer.com Privacy Policy | Cox Automotive | Dealer.com

## **Dealer Dot Com, Inc.: Website Privacy Policy**

Dealer Dot Com, Inc. (“Dealer.com”) takes your privacy seriously and is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Because we do gather certain types of information from visitors to our sites, we have developed a privacy statement to help you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This statement discloses the types of information we gather, how it is used, and how you can gain access to and edit any data that we’ve collected about you at any time.

Dealer.com has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe’s program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the Web site www.dealer.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us here. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

**Guiding Principles:**

Dealer.com respects the privacy of individuals who visit our Web sites, send us e-mail, or participate in features/services we offer online. Accordingly, our policy regarding online privacy has been developed using the following guiding principles:

Dealer.com collects information online primarily to provide our visitors with a more relevant experience on our sites. When doing so, we will make every reasonable effort to avoid excessive or irrelevant collection of data. Dealer.com will take reasonable physical, electronic and managerial measures to safeguard and secure any information you provide to us (e.g. data will be stored in protected databases on secured servers with restricted access). Dealer.com will not share any information you’ve provided to us with anyone without your consent other than to provide the service you’ve requested.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Data:**

Anytime you visit our Web site, we may gather certain non-personally identifiable information regarding the means you use to access our site. This information may include the type and version of your browser, your service provider, your IP address, any search engine you may have used to locate the site, and navigational information about where you go on our Web sites. We use this information to better serve you, help diagnose problems with our server, administer the Web site, and compile broad statistical data. If we associate non-personally identifiable information with personally identifiable information, we will consider that combination of data as personally identifiable and treat it in the ways described within this privacy policy.

**Information Voluntarily Provided:**

Any information you provide to us (such as your name, e-mail address, phone number and company) when you register for an event, “Contact Us,” request newsletters, information, or use any of the other interactive portions of our Web sites, is securely maintained. This information may be used to provide you with information you’ve requested about our company, our products and our services, or to provide you with special notices. You may opt out of receiving future communications at any time (see opt-out procedures below). This data may also be used to tailor your experience on our sites by providing content that is relevant to your interests and geographic region.

**Disclosure of Personal Information:**

Dealer.com understands the importance of your privacy. We collect and maintain the personal information for our use and our subsidiaries. We do not sell, rent, or trade consumer information to third parties, other than as described below.

Business Partners:

Dealer.com may partner with select retailers and other companies at various times to provide expanded services to our site visitors. As part of such a relationship, we may share with these companies the use of certain interactive Web site functions (e.g., when registering for events). Information provided by site visitors through the use of such interactive functions may be available to both Dealer.com and our partners.  In addition, note that such third parties may provide access to additional privacy policies related to the service, which should be reviewed by you.

Service Providers:

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as submitting email communications to you on our behalf. These companies are authorized to use your personal information  _only as necessary_  to provide these services to us.

Business Transfers:

In the event that Dealer.com sells or transfers a particular portion of its business assets, user information may be one of the business assets transferred as part of the transaction. If substantially all of the assets of Dealer.com are acquired, user information may be transferred as part of the acquisition.

Compliance with Law/Safety:

Dealer.com may disclose specific personal information based on a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to comply with or conform to the law or that such disclosure is necessary to protect the users of our Web sites, the sites themselves, or the public.

With Consent:

Other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, you will be notified when any personally-identifiable information about you may be shared with third parties, and you will be given the prior opportunity to decline to share that information.

**Use of Cookies and Other Technologies:**

Dealer.com, and its third party analytics partners, may use a browser feature known as a “cookie.” Cookies are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing you with a customized browsing experience. Dealer.com uses cookies to provide you with the convenience of not having to reenter information, such as your contact details, multiple times during your visits to our Web sites. Cookies can also be utilized to help us provide you with information targeted to your interests, based upon your prior browsing on our Web sites. The “help” section of the toolbar on most browsers will inform you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you upon the receipt of a new cookie, or how to disable the use of cookies completely. As our Web sites have been designed to take advantage of the use of cookies, should you configure your browser to decline their use, certain features of our Web sites may not function correctly and you may be required to reenter information more frequently.  Third parties may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use this website.

Web Beacons / Gifs:

Our third party web analytics partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. The information gathered by clear gifs is not tied to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

Flash LSOs:

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to assist us with the display of video content on our site.  Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.  Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies.  To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:

<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

Third Party Tracking:

Third parties may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use this website.

**Correcting, Updating, Deleting Your Information:**

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, ask to have it removed from a public forum or testimonial on our site by contacting us via one of the methods listed below.  We will respond to your request within 30 days.

**Data Retention:**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**External Links:**

Our Web sites contain links to other sites. Any such links are provided solely as a convenience to you. Dealer.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. To help ensure the protection of your privacy, we recommend that you review the privacy policy of any site you visit via a link from one of our Web sites.

**Public Forums:**

Our Web sites may make blog comment areas, chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users at various times. Please remember that, unless otherwise stated, any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in these areas.

**Testimonials:**

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us via one of the methods listed below.

**Social Media Widgets:**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Security:**

The security of your personal information is important to us.  We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Opt-out Procedures:**

Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us via one of the methods listed below.

**Browser-Based Do Not Track:**

Some browsers incorporate a “Do Not Track” (DNT) feature that, when turned on, signals to websites and online services that you do not want to be tracked. Because there is not yet an accepted standard for how to respond to a DNT signal, we do not currently respond to DNT signals on this website or on websites where we provide advertisements, content, or other services.

**Children’s Privacy:**

This web site is not directed to children under the age of thirteen, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the site. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on the site, we will delete the information from our records.

**Updates to Our Privacy Policy:**

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically to reflect changes in our online information practices.  If we make any material changes, we will notify you by a prominent notice on our site.  Please check back from time to time to be aware of any changes to the Privacy Policy.

**Agreement to Privacy Policy:**

Your use of this site constitutes acceptance of the provisions of the Dealer.com Privacy Policy and your continued usage after such changes are posted constitutes acceptance of each revised Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any revised policy, please exit the site immediately.

**Contacting the Web Sites:**

If you have questions concerning this Privacy Policy or the practices of these sites, you may contact us by clicking here, by calling 802.658.0965, or by writing to us at Dealer.com, 1 Howard Street, Burlington, Vermont 05401.

**Your California Privacy Rights:**

This PRIVACY NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS supplements the information contained in the Privacy Statement of Dealer.com. and its subsidiaries (collectively, “we,” “us,” or “our”), a Cox Automotive, Inc. company, and applies solely to consumers who reside in the State of California (“consumers” or “you”). We adopt this notice to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”) and other California privacy laws.  Any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this notice.

_Information We Collect_

We collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with an individual consumer, household, or device (“personal information”). We have collected the following categories of personal information from consumers within the last twelve (12) months:

The following examples are taken directly from California Consumer Privacy Act, Dealer.com collects at least one of the example items from each category.

**Category** | **Examples** | **Collected**  
---|---|---  
A. Identifiers. | A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, Social Security number, driver’s license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers. | YES  
B. Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)). | A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver’s license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information. Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. | YES  
C. Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law. | Age (40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic information). | YES  
D. Commercial information. | Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. | YES  
E. Biometric information. | Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as, fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retina scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data. | NO  
F. Internet or other similar network activity. | Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer’s interaction with a website, application, or advertisement. | YES  
G. Geolocation data. | Physical location or movements. | YES  
H. Sensory data. | Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information. | NO  
I. Professional or employment-related information. | Current or past job history or performance evaluations. | YES  
J. Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99)). | Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records. | NO  
K. Inferences drawn from other personal information. | Profile reflecting a person’s preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes. | YES  
  
We obtain the categories of personal information listed above from the following categories of sources:

  * Directly from our customers or their agents. For example, from documents that our clients provide to us related to the services for which they engage us.
  * Indirectly from our clients or their agents. For example, through information we collect from our clients in the course of providing services to them.
  * Directly and indirectly from activity on our client’s website.
  * From third-parties that interact with us in connection with the services we offer and/or perform.

_Sharing Personal Information_

We may disclose your personal information to a third party for a business purpose.  When we disclose personal information for a business purpose, we enter a contract that describes the purpose and requires the recipient to both keep that personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose except performing the contract.

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have disclosed the following categories of personal information for a business purpose:

Category A:             Identifiers.  
Category B:             California Customer Records personal information categories.  
Category D:             Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.

Category F:            Internet or other similar network activity.  
Category I:              Professional or employment-related information.

Category K:            Inferences drawn of other personal information

We disclose your personal information for a business purpose to the following categories of third parties:

  * Our affiliates.
  * Service providers.
  * Third parties to whom our customers have authorized us to disclose their personal information in connection to services we provide to them.

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have not sold any personal information.

_Your Rights and Choices_

The CCPA provides California residents with specific rights regarding their personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and explains how to exercise those rights.

_Access to Specific Information and Data Portability Rights_

You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we will disclose to you:

  * The categories of personal information we collected about you.
  * The categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you.
  * Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling that personal information.
  * The categories of third parties with whom we share that personal information.
  * The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).
  * If we sold or disclosed your personal information for a business purpose, two separate lists disclosing: 
    * sales, identifying the personal information categories that each category of recipient purchased; and
    * disclosures for a business purpose, identifying the personal information categories that each category of recipient obtained.

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 entitles California users to request information concerning whether a business has disclosed certain information about you to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. California users who wish to request further information in compliance with this law or have questions or concerns about our privacy practices and policies may contact us as specified in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

_Deletion Request Rights_

You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected about you and retained, subject to certain exceptions in the CCPA. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we will delete your personal information from our records, unless an exception applies, and we will direct our service providers to similarly delete your personal information from their records.

_Exercising Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights_

To exercise the access, data portability, and deletion rights described above, please submit a “verifiable consumer request” (defined below) to us by either:

  * Calling us at (888) 576-1547

  * Visiting Dealer.com/CPA

Only you or someone you authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. You may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child.

A verifiable consumer request must:

  * Provide enough information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative; and
  * Describe your request with enough detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.

You may only make a verifiable consumer request for access or data portability twice within a 12-month period.

We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you.  Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us.  We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.

_Non-Discrimination_

We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. Unless permitted by the CCPA, we will not deny you goods or services, charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties, provide you a different level or quality of goods or services, or suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.

_Do Not Track_

Online Tracking Policy for California Residents. As of the effective date of this Privacy Statement, there is no commonly accepted response for Do Not Track signals initiated by browsers, therefore we do not respond to them.

_Contact Information_

If you have any questions or comments about this notice, our Privacy Statement, the ways in which we collect and use your personal information, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under California law, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

Website: www.dealer.com  
Email: [privacy@coxautoinc.com  
](mailto:privacy@coxautoinc.com)Postal Address: Cox Automotive, Inc.  
Attn: Scott Hilsen, Chief Compliance & Privacy Officer  
6205 Peachtree Dunwoody Rd. NE  
Atlanta, Ga 30328
